Hanging around here won't do any good.
Let's head back to the ship for now.
We left Nami there all by ourself.
And Robin's still missing.
The ship's a problem, too.
Yeah.
Hey, Luffy!
I've made a decision.
About the ship.
It's time to part ways with the Mary.
We'll say goodbye to her here.
Big fight under the moon.
The pirate flag flutters with sorrow.
Hey!
Usopp's finally awake, you guys!
All right!
Good to hear!
That's one less thing to worry about.
Hey, Usopp!
Robin still isn't back yet.
You know, I ought to punch you for scaring us like that.
Yeah, no kidding.
Though it looks like you've taken enough punches already, if you ask me.
What were you thinking, taking those guys on alone?
You can't just run off and fight whoever you want.
Oh, that's a good one coming from you.
This wouldn't have happened if I was strong like you guys.
I'm sorry!
It's all my fault!
I'm so ashamed of myself!
I knew how important that money was to us!
Hey, hey, stop!
I get it!
I know you're sorry, but you don't have to get all touchy-feely on me, okay?
With all our savings!
All the trouble we went through!
What about the Mary?
Take it easy!
You shouldn't be out of bed yet!
Come on, calm down!
Stop your whining and listen to the doctor!
So, is there a chance we might get our money back after all?
Well, maybe.
We won't know for sure till that Frankie guy shows up.
I see.
I'm sorry.
Hey!
Even if we can't get the rest back, we still have a hundred million berries left over!
Don't worry!
Yeah, but he lost twice that much!
Nami!
Sorry, Yusup.
No.
It's fine.
More importantly, is Mary gonna be okay?
I mean, can we get her repaired with the money that we have left?
We're lucky we have all these awesome shipwrights to work on her.
But I know things are gonna get rough out there, so I want her to be stronger than ever before!
We gotta do a lot more than just a little touch-up.
So, do you think those guys will still do a good job if we only have a hundred million to pay with?
You talked to them about it, right?
Uh, yeah.
But we aren't having them repair it.
We decided to get a new ship instead!
I know that we probably should have asked you first, but we didn't have much choice.
Either way, I've made up my mind.
The Going Mary has taken good care of us, but it looks like our journey with her has to end here.
Anyway, Ice Pops gave us this awesome ship catalog to flip through.
There's all kinds of different ships we could pick from in here.
And if we decided to shop for a used model, we could go bigger than the Mary.
And still keep our budget under a hundred million.
Wait.
Just stop.
I get it, Luffy.
But the joke's gone on long enough, okay?
See?
Chopper doesn't know you're kidding.
Look how upset this is making him.
Jeez, Captain.
You should know better than to treat your crew like that.
Come on, Nami.
Back me up here.
Hold up.
Does that mean we don't have enough for the repairs?
It's because I lost the 200 million, isn't it?
And now we can't afford the work on the Mary.
Is that what this is about?
After all, a first-class shipyard is going to cost a lot, right?
Would you stop and listen to me?
What is it?
Tell me!
Don't try to sugarcoat it!
I'm not, okay?
I don't even care that you lost all the money.
That's over now!
If that's how you feel, then what's with all this crap about buying a new ship?
Both of you, stop it!
Fighting isn't going to help.
Just calm down for a sec.
I don't see what I'm doing wrong.
He's the one saying all this dumb stuff!
I know how you feel, but you shouldn't get so worked up right now.
Listen to Nami, Usopp.
If you don't get any rest, you're not going to get better.
Who cares about me?
How can you just sit here when he's making jokes about getting a new ship?
I'm not joking about anything!
This was a hard decision for me, too!
Oh, yeah, I feel really sorry for you!
Already window shopping for a new toy!
You trying to pick a fight with me?
I don't want your damn pity, got it?
If you tell me it doesn't matter that I lost the money,
then why are you talking about buying a new ship?
Just spit it out already!
If we can't afford the repairs because I screwed up, then tell me!
Don't show me some stupid catalog and change the subject!
I want to know the truth!
The Mary can't be!
What?
What did you just say?
Don't make me repeat myself!
I told you, the Mary can't be repaired anymore!
No matter what we do, we...
We can't fix it!
Otherwise, I wouldn't say something like that!
You mean this ship?
The ship that we're riding on right now is broken?
That's right!
It's only a matter of time before she sinks!
What are you talking about, Luffy?
That's nuts!
No, I'm serious!
The shipwrights took a look at the Mary themselves!
They said she wouldn't even hold out until the next island!
And it's settled, so that's it?
A bunch of strangers tell you to scrap your ship and you don't even ask any questions?
That's enough!
I understand these guys know what they're talking about, but this is just wrong!
Don't give up on the Mary!
What about all the adventures we've gone on together?
What about all the battles we've fought?
She's our friend!
She's one of us!
Are you going to abandon her for another ship without a second thought?
After all we've been through, is that how little the Mary meets to you, Luffy?
I know you're upset, Usopp, but you need to calm down!
Sorry, but no!
I'm not packing down until we settle this!
Usopp, please!
What?
So you know better than the shipwrights?
If we had someone on the crew who knew about this stuff, we wouldn't have asked them in the first place!
Then forget them!
We don't need those guys telling us what to do!
I'll repair the Mary myself, just like before!
We've made it this far, so there's no reason we can't go on that way!
Here, I'll get started right now!
Come on, guys, help me out!
That's not gonna work!
That's right, we don't have enough lumber, do we?
I better go buy some at the shipyard!
We've got a lot of work to do!
You're not a shipwright, Usopp!
You hear me?!
Stop it, Luffy!
Yeah, you're right, I know!
But so what?
I don't see why you're so hung up on everything those stupid shipwrights say!
If they knew what she'd gone through, they wouldn't give up on the Mary so easy!
They just want your money!
Usopp?
The Mary's our ship, so it's our job to take care of her without someone else butting in!
I'm not giving up!
I won't let them take the Mary away from me!
This is stupid!
You got fooled by a bunch of salesmen trying to pawn off a used boat!
Luffy I know wouldn't cave in to some sales bitch from a total stranger!
He'd believe in the strength of the Mary and the strength of his crew!
But here you are, acting like you know everything and ignoring your friends!
I can't believe that's the kind of captain you turned out to be!
I thought you were better than that!
You're not being fair, Usopp!
Luffy felt that...
You stay out of this!
It was my call, I stand by it!
There's nothing you can do!
We're getting a new ship, whether you like it or not!
This is the end of the road for the Mary!
I'm not leaving her here!
I don't care what you say!
I know you're always trying to think about the future, but not every one of this crew is like that!
I see the Mary as one of our friends, got it?
And I won't abandon her when she's hers!
Don't be stupid!
Even if she is a friend, that doesn't mean she's a person!
She is to me, and she still has the strength to live!
But you wouldn't appreciate that, because all you care about is getting a new ship to play with!
Alright, that's enough!
Stop being so selfish and think about your crew!
Dude, listen to yourself!
Luffy, don't act like you're the only one who's torn up about this!
We all feel the same way!
If that was true, then you wouldn't be looking for a new ship!
Alright, fine!
If you don't like the way your captain does things, then why don't you go ahead and get on-
Sanji!
This is going way too far!
What the hell is wrong with you?
If you don't watch it, you're going to say something you can't take back, so calm down!
Yeah, I'm sorry.
I don't know what I was thinking.
You don't have to apologize, because that's how you really feel, isn't it?
That's not true!
Just get rid of your dead weight and move on before they can slow you down!
If you're going to throw away the Mary, might as well throw me away too!
I know you're pissed off, but don't say stupid crap like that!
No, I'm serious.
I've been thinking about this for a while now.
It isn't like it was before.
You guys are just too strong for me.
I can't keep up anymore.
I mean, look what happened today.
You can't even trust me with your money.
There's no point in keeping me around if all I do is cause you trouble.
You don't want weak people on your crew, do you?
Luffy, I still believe that you'll be king of the pirates one day.
But as for me, I'm just lucky I was able to make it this far.
Even back when we first met and I was going to set off alone,
you probably just invited me on your ship out of pity.
What are you talking about?
Get on already.
We're friends, right? So get on.
That's the only reason I'm here.
There's no sense traveling together if we don't even have the same goal.
Hey, Usopp, where are you going?
Wherever I go, it's my business.
It has nothing to do with you anymore.
Sorry, guys.
I'm leaving the crew.
This is goodbye.
Goodbye.
Usopp, why?
Oh, no.
Hey, don't just sit there, Luffy.
Who knows what he's going to do out there.
Go say something to him.
Stop him before it's too late.
We've come too far together.
We can't part ways like this.
Usopp's not just a crew member.
He's one of our friends too, isn't he?
Get off and stop him!
Luffy, what's wrong?
Please, you're the captain, aren't you?
Fine.
Have it your way then.
Uthopp!
Get back here!
It shouldn't be like this!
Come on, we can talk!
Yeah, come back!
I want you to stay!
Don't leave us!
Uthopp, please!
Say something.
Luffy, I'm sorry I can't follow you anymore.
And I'm sorry I was a pain till the bitter end.
I know you're the captain of this ship, so the Mary belongs to you.
That's why I want you to fight me, Monkey D. Luffy.
I challenge you to a duel!
Whoa, wait, what are you saying?
At 10 o'clock tonight, I'll be back.
So you better be ready for a fight, Captain.
I can't stop you from destroying your own ship.
But if I win, I'm taking the Mary and leaving.
Either way, when we're done, the last bond between us will be broken.
What's with you?
Would you stop this nonsense already?
Usopp just got worked up because things were moving too fast, right?
That's no reason to fight with your own friend, especially when he's hurt.
If you give it some time, I'm sure both of you will see how silly this is.
You've gone too far to turn back now.
That's not true.
There's nothing stopping you from apologizing and talking it over one more time.
Like I said, no turning back.
And why not?
Usopp is willing to risk his life to fight me.
He's more than just angry.
Besides, if just talking it over was enough to make things right,
we wouldn't have come to this in the first place.
That's all I have to say, so goodnight.
Luffy.
Think about it.
You said the Frankie family came here this afternoon, right?
Yeah.
So, what are you trying to say?
If you hadn't let them off so easy,
they wouldn't have stolen the money from us in the first place.
It's your fault those guys attacked Usopp.
He's just freaking out because he feels guilty.
Hey, don't go blaming me for not kicking their asses hard enough.
You were the one who ran off to go shopping.
What am I supposed to cook if I don't have any food?
Both of you, shut up!
There's been enough fighting already.
Whatever happened, it's over now.
Oh, I know.
But this wouldn't be happening if it wasn't for him.
Oh, hey.
You're back.
You were going after Usopp, weren't you?
Even if he was mad, I still wanted to treat his wounds.
But he turned me away.
He found a place to stay.
So, at least he can get some rest.
But do you know what he said to me?
He said we aren't friends now.
So, I should leave him alone and go back to the ship.
Just this morning, we were all so happy.
And now what?
We lost Usopp.
Robin's still missing.
I feel like if we don't do something,
the whole crew is going to fall apart.
Well, the straw hats, huh?
I have a bad feeling about tonight.
I wonder what it is.
It's ten o'clock.
Usopp will be here any second now.
Listen up.
I don't want any of you leaving the ship.
You got that?
Look.
Please don't fight!
Wait!
ORCHESTRA PLAYS
So you didn't lose your nerve after all.
No matter how this battle ends, you can't regret it.
This is exactly what you asked for.
That's perfect.
Don't go easy on me.
I won't be the underdog this time.
In fact, I've already figured out a way to defeat you.
On the next One Piece Luffy vs Usopp collision of two men's prides
I'm gonna be king of the pirates